Inventory of the Robert Olney Easton papers, circa 1861-1999
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
- Research Files, circa 1861-1996; Series I.
  - University of Wyoming – 100 Years of Western Literature Symposium:
    - Clippings, 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folders 11-12)
    - Correspondence, January-October 1992 (Box 23, Folders 1-2)
    - Notes, 1990-1992 (Box 23, Folders 3-5)
    - Pamphlets, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Periodicals, 1990-1992 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Civil Engineering Laboratory:
    - Clippings, 1964-1967 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Periodicals:
      - Antarctic Journal of the United States, May-June 1969 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - The Military Engineer, 1962-1965 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Naval Research News, 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Navy Civil Engineer, 1964-1969 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Publications:
      - Can Do!, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - The Story of NCEL, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Summary of U.S. Naval Civil Engineering Laboratory Related to Cargo Handling, August 1966 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Reports:
      - Activity Summary, Fiscal ’68, Naval Civil Engineering Laboratory, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - FY 1968 Report on Independent Research and Independent Exploratory Development Programs, September 1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Ocean Engineer: Undersea Warfare Mission Area Committee, First Progress Report, March 14, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Reprint – The Effects of Ship Motions on the Mohole Drilling Rig, from Naval Research Bulletins, June 1963 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Wild Challenge:
    - Clippings, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Periodical – Argosy, February 1952 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The Wind of Pelican Island, Periodical – Atlantic Monthly, October 1942 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Woman, Correspondence, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Women and Dynamite, Periodical – Atlantic Monthly, July 1942 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1942-1999; Series II.
  - Brand, Max (Frederick Faust), 1942 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Closed to public until 2050
  - Schaefer, Jack, 1955-1976 (Box 25, Folders 2-12)
  - Suez Crisis, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - University of Wyoming, 1968-1973, 1977-1999 (Box 26, Folders 2-8)
- Personal Files, 1928-1996; Series III.
  - Clippings:
    - Easton, Robert, 1942-1996 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Easton, Robert – Early Writings, 1928-1940 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1958-1982 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Diary, Trip to Europe, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript, V-E Day, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Periodicals:
    - The Californians, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - La Reata, Fall 1984 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Santa Barbara Magazine, 1993, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Publication, Capra Press, Fall 1982 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1861-1957; Series IV.
  - Photographs, circa 1879, circa 1905; Subseries 1.
    - Austin, Mary, circa 1905 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Chief Iron Tail, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Custer, General George A., undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - McCarty, William H., aka “Billy the Kid,”, circa 1879 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Transparencies, 1953-1957; Subseries 2.
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer:
      - The Cave Tigers of Hong Kong, from True, January 1953 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Death of the Bullet Proof Bandit, from True, July 1957 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - The Death of Malunga, from True, July 1953 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Escape With a Mint, from True, March 1956 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - The Last Sea Otter Hunt, from True, July 1956 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - The Pyramids of Shensi, from True, March 1955 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Twelve Days on the Dragon’s Throne, from True, November 1953 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Unidentified, from True, 1950s (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Wild Camel Hunt in Tibet, from True, December 1955 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Photo Negatives, circa 1861-circa 1952; Subseries 3.
    - The Book of the American West – “Guns of the American West,”, undated (Box 28, Folders 1-4)
    - Hopkins, Frank T., “Three of his favorite horses with Buffalo Bill Show: Darkie, Blaze, Blueskin,”, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - McCarty, William H., aka “Billy the Kid,”, circa 1879 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer, circa 1861-circa 1952 (Box 28, Folders 7-13)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Alaska-Yukon, 1895, 1947 (Box 28, Folders 14-16)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – California, 1890s (Box 28, Folders 17-23)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China, circa 1909-1917 (Box 28, Folders 24-65)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China and Mongolia, circa 1909-1917 (Box 28, Folders 66-74)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Mongolia, circa 1909-1917 (Box 28, Folders 75-89)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Philippines, Schroder with friends in Manila, 1909 (Box 28, Folder 90)
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – Siberia, Near replica of the “Ralph J. Long,” drawing by R.H. Palenske, undated (Box 28, Folder 91)
  - Photo Negatives – Nitrates, circa 1909-1917; Subseries 4.
    - Schroder, Fred Meyer – China, circa 1909-1917 (Box 28, Folders 92-95)
      (In envelope)
- Books, 1943-1996; Series V.
  - Easton, Robert:
    - Guns, Gold, and Caravans, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - The Happy Man, 1943, 1977, 1993 (Box 29, Folders 2-4)
    - Max Brand: The Big “Westerner,”, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - The Saga of California: This Promised Land, 1982, 1996 (Box 29, Folders 6-7)
    - The Saga of California: Power and Glory, 1989, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Easton, Robert and Brown, MacKenzie, Lord of the Beasts: The Saga of Buffalo Jones:
    - 1961 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - 1964 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Easton, Robert and Easton, Jane, Love and War; Pearl Harbor Through V-J Day, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Gilbar, Steven and Stewart, Dean, Tales of Santa Barbara: From Native Storytellers to Sue Grafton, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Oversized, 1890s-1964; Series VI.
  - Newspapers, Right Turn in the Rockies, 1962-1964 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album, Schroder, Fred Meyer, 1890s-1917 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Photostats, Schroder, Fred Meyer, 1899-1953 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    (Includes rolled photostats)